# Travis Stephenson

# **Proficiencies**

#### **Technologies**

HTML JavaScript CSS JavaScript/jQuery/Bootstrap Elixir/Erlang MySQL Mongo DB C#

#### **General Familiarity**

Python Postman Ruby API's ReactJS

# **Skills/Proficiencies**

Microsoft Visual Studio Microsoft Visual Studio Code

Git Jira Suite Slack Figma

Unity

#### **QA and Project Management**

16 years of experience with quality assurance testing with construction materials. Quality Assurance principles and methods translate to other industries, identifying issues with the product so they can be resolved. Engineering processes that streamline and optimize finding product issues. As a Project Manager, I have proven skills in planning, maintaining, and hitting sprint schedules using the Agile development method. With CI/CD principles many projects have been planned and implemented and are currently being supported by my teams.

#### Education

# Bachelor of Computer Science degree candidate; anticipated completion May 2023

Have completed various courses on Scripting & Programming Applications, Software, Software QA, Data management, and more.

# Utah Valley University, Orem Utah Associate in Science (AS) in General Studies March 2016 to March 2018

Completed courses C#, UI/UX Web Design, Web Essentials, Scripting Internet Technology. Continually teaching myself about new technologies including programming languages, programs, and their use and application in the real world.

## Interests/Hobbies

Family Drone Videography

Editing Videography

# Experience

#### **Contracted Web Developer**

March 2014-Present

Designed, tested, and maintained websites using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript with J Query and Bootstrap with API data storage in MongoDB for various customers, some of these include South Valley Compounding Pharmacy, Byzantec, and Field of Dreams MLB Vacations LLC.

- Created and oversaw wireframe designs from client requests.
- Created responsive, straightforward, functional UI to allow visitors on any device to have the same experience.
- Built API following RESTful standards to allow customers to submit data stored using MongoDB.
- Oversaw updates and QA testing of websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed
- Committed over 100 website changes to improve user flow and understanding of platform experiences and features.
- Automated test development for websites using Elixir and Selenium

## Geneva Rock Products - Orem, UT **Quality Control Engineer**

February 2006-April 2021

Provided Quality Assurance Materials Testing in a variety of projects for both the Local, State, and Federal Government entities. Designed Asphalt Mixes to meet the specifications of the job. 16 years of experience holding all relevant certifications (8) in total for AASHTO/ASTM construction materials testing. Learned at taught my colleagues Stonemont Quality Control and Mix Design software. An industry leader in testing for quality, providing troubleshooting during production and winning Lab of the year 2021 and 2019.

- Monitored, created, and populated QA results sheets with Stonemont QC Database with MySQL.
- Managed a QA team that provided all the manual and automated testing for numerous local, state, and federal projects many of which won Project of the Year Awards.
- Overhauled Training and Onboarding programs to standardize our process. This included manuals and quarterly testing as well as producing training videos for the program.

#### Appstango-Lehi, UT

#### **Project Manager/Scoping Master April 2021-Present**

As Project Manager, I am responsible for new and existing customers and the app development lifecycle. I am responsible for the customer journey through the entire development and QA process. This includes ensuring that all aspects of the communication, planning and implementation of app development are well-managed. Have technical experience with every phase of software development from Scoping/Design to Agile development in Jira. Have overseen numerous projects currently in development.